萌月&諸神字幕組
目覚めては繰り返す
Day after day, I awake in a daze,
mezamete ha kurikaesu nemui asa ha
目覚めては繰り返す　眠い朝は
眠い朝は
襟のタイをきつく締め
And fasten my collar tightly.
eri no tai wo kitsuku shime
襟のタイをきつく締め
教室のドアくぐると
As I walk through the door to my classroom,
kyoushitsu no doa kuguru to hon no sukoshi
教室のドアくぐるとほんの少し
ほんの少し胸を張って歩き出せる
I have the slightest bit of pride.
mune wo hatte arukidaseru
胸を張って歩き出せる
Then a wind rushed through that normal, everyday life.
sonna nichijou ni fukinukeru kaze
そんな日常に吹き抜ける風
そんな日常に
吹き抜ける風
聞こえた気がした　感じた気がしたんだ
I have a feeling I can hear it,
kikoeta ki ga shita
聞こえた気がした
I have a feeling I can sense it,
kanjita ki ga shitanda
感じた気がしたんだ
震えだす 今この胸で
Beginning to tremble within my chest.
furuedasu ima kono mune de
震え出す今この胸で
I have a feeling it's on its way,
mou kuru ki ga shita
もう来る気がした
As the millions of stars began to disappear,
ikuoku no hoshi ga kiesatteku no wo
幾億の星が消え去ってくのを
I sent them on their way,
miokutta
見送った
見送った 手を振った
Waving my hand,
te wo futta
手を振った
良かったねと
Whispering, "Congratulations".
yokatta ne, to
よかったね、と
Okay, this "AD". Who knows what this means?
はい　いいか　このADとはどういう意味か
わかる人…
The day... it's finally come.
ついに　この時期がやってきたか
Anti-Tenshi Operation HQ
What? Is something starting?
なんだ
なんか始まるのか
Oh yeah.
Tenshi will be starting her assault.
天使の猛攻が始まる
Uh huh.
天使の猛攻…
Tenshi assaulting?
A-An assault? But why?
猛攻って　どうしてなんだ
Because exams are coming up.
テストが近いから
Yeah!
ああ　なぜ
Um, why?
考えればわかるでしょ～
Think about it a little.
授業を受けさせることも大事ですが
It's important to make us attend class,
but it's also important she force us to take tests and do well on them.
テストを受けさせてイイ点を取らせること
それも大事なことです
天使にとっては
To Tenshi, that is.
However, this exam period could turn out to be a good chance for us to retaliate against her.
けど　このテスト期間
逆に天使を陥れる
大きなチャンスとなりえるかもしれない
Looks like you got an idea, Yurippe.
何か思いついたみたいだな～　ゆりっぺ
聞かせてもらうぜ
Let's hear it.
We'll be a nuisance to Tenshi day after day and
work to make her fail as many exams as possible.
天使のテストのじゃまを徹底的に行い
赤点を取らせまくる
And with that she'll drop to the bottom of the school rankings.
そして　校内順位最下位に突き落とす
それが何になるの
What happens then?
Loss of honour.
名誉の失意
Will she be able to maintain her
dignity as the student council president?
翻譯夏矢今瘋
臺本眯眯 奔奔
生徒会長として
彼女は威厳を保っていられるかしら
You're saying something like that would weaken her?
それで弱くなると
At the very least, the teachers and the
students will start seeing her differently.
特效 saber 時間&後期 月染不透
校對　矢今瘋小夜子
すくなくとも
教師や一般生徒の見る目が変わるわ
As a result, a change we have yet to see will come about.
その行いにはいままでなかった変化が生じる
萌月諸神聯合譯製
どんな
What kind?
さあ　そこまで私には読めない
I wonder. I can't predict that far.
Then are you sure there's a point to doing this?
じゃ　意味がないんじゃないのか
けど
But, if she is not an angel created by God, and doesn't have a tin man's heart...
彼女がもし神の創造物である天使なんかではなく
その精神が鋼でないなら
私たちと同じヒトの魂であるなら
If she has a human soul like us...
Then the loss of honour will cause some emotional conflict.
その名誉の失意は
彼女に精神的な打撃をあたえることになる
First, we'll decide upon the members taking part in this operation.
まずは今回の作戦メンバーを決める
天使のクラスでテストを受けるための根回しは
I've already arranged for us to be in the same classroom as Tenshi while taking the exam.
すでに完了しているわ
じゃあメンバー全員で
Then can't we just distract her as a group?
かためちまったらいいんじゃねえか
Keep your "can't we just" to yourself! We can't fail this mission.
じゃねえか…じゃないわよ
ミスは許されないんだから
作戦が途中でばれたら
If the operation leaks,
私たちはすぐにも別の教室に移されて
we'll be moved to a different classroom and won't have the chance to make Tenshi fail.
天使に赤点を取らせる細工ができなくなるのよ
なるほど　ならオレはパスだ
I see.
Then I'll pass.
そういうのはメメシイやつらの出番だ
This kinda work is for sissies.
In that case, the team will be:
そこで　今回のメンバーは
Takamatsu-kun,
高松君
Hinata-kun,
日向君
大山君　竹山君
Ooyama-kun, Takeyama-kun,
and Otonashi-kun.
音無君
I-I'm involved again?
またオレかよ
ボクのことは「クライスト」と
Call me Christ, pl-
I simply chose the most normal-looking bunch.
見た目が普通のやつらを選んだだけよ
それじゃ　オペレーションスタート
So...
Operation, start!
The seating will be decided on the day of, based on lottery.
テストの席はその日の朝
くじ引きで決定される
Classroom
Classroom Building B
これで　天使のちかくの席でないと
If we can't get a seat near Tenshi,
our conspiracy against her will be difficult.
細工は一気に困難になるわ
イイ　あの席の前を引き当てなさい
Listen up. Be sure you get the seat in front of her.
んなムチャ言うなよ
Don't ask for the impossible.
Let's see.
20.
二十　外れた
Bummer.
十一　天使からは遠いですね
11.
I'm far away from Tenshi.
33.
三十三　全然ダメだ
Completely useless.
So, my turn.
オレか
二十五
25.
Man. I'm far, too.
と　オレも遠いな～
Look, I drew number one!
一番よ
って なによ　この　この
Like that's useful!
Isn't anyone close to her?!
近くに誰かいないの
Front, side, or wherever!
横でも前でもいいから
I'm in front of her.
一つ前です
よしゃッ
Way to go!
So, what am I supposed to do?
で　なにをすればイイんですか
When the answer sheets get passed out, hold on to two.
答案用紙が配られる際
二枚持っておきなさい
その一方を回収するときに
When collecting them, swap it with Tenshi's answer sheet.
天使のものとすりかえる
そっちの答案用紙は白紙に
On the blank sheet-
Actually, turning it completely blank will be too suspicious.
お　いや
白紙じゃ逆に不自然にとられるわね
Fill it in with ridiculous answers.
バカみたいなの答案を並べておいて
Easier said than done.
と言われましても
Write down things like what you want to be in the future.
上から将来なりたいものを書き連ねておきなさい
It's a Physics test, you know...
物理のテストですが
イイのよ　飛行機のパイロットとか
Who cares? Write something like "airplane pilot" or "dolphin trainer."
イルカの飼育員とか書いておきなさい
相当のバカだな～
Those really are idiotic.
回収の時はどうするんですか
How do you propose we accomplish this during the pick-up?
Hinata-kun! Do stunts at the right time to grab everyone's attention.
日向君
タイミングを見計らって
アクションを起こしなさい
全員がそっちに注目するように
んなムチャな～
You've gotta be kidding me.
あなたは何のために入れたと思ってるのよ
Why do you think I put you in this operation?
What?! You added me in to be a clown?
まさか　そんな「道化師役」とは
で　その瞬間を見計らって
At that moment,
竹山君が後ろの席の回収し終えた答案用紙から
Takeyama-kun will take Tenshi's answer sheet out of the collected pile and swap it with a fake copy.
天使の用紙を引き抜き
にせものとすりかえる
とにかく
In any case, even if something unplanned happens, we'll watch each other's backs. Got it?
想定外なことが起きても
慌てず
みんなでフォローしあって行くのよ　イイ
Ah. Hang on a moment, please.
でも待ってください
名前の欄にはいったいなんで書けばいいんでしょ～
What should I write in the name block?
"Tenshi."
天使
阿呆か
Are you an idiot? Wouldn't "Student Council President" be better?
生徒会長って…通るんじゃねえ
そうだよね
Yeah, since she's supposed to be stupid enough to answer "dolphin trainer."
どうせイルカの飼育員とか答えるくらいバカなんだから
No, it'd be too stupid to not even have the name written correctly!
いやいや　自分の名前ぐらい書けなきゃ阿呆すぎるだろ～
つーか　お前らが名前知らないのが驚きだよ
Rather, I'm surprised that none of you know her real name!
There's been no opportunity to learn it.
知る機会なんてなかったもの
よくなかったな～
How is that possible?!
じゃ　あんた調べてきてよ
Then why don't you go find out?
職員室行って名簿見てきて
Go to the Faculty Lounge and find it in the student roster.
チッ ったく
For God's sake. Can't they be more-
もうちょっと
どこ行くの
Where are you going?
The test is about to start.
テスト始まるわよ
Oh, no, I... I'm getting a little nervous.
あ　いや　緊張してきて
Damn. What should I do?
クソ
どうしよう
I feel bad that her test will be turned in as "Student Council President."
名前が生徒会長で提出されるなんて
かわいそうじゃないか
いやいや　それどころか
Or rather, when asked,
二十オームの抵抗に三点ゼロボルトの電圧を加えたとき
"When a voltage of 3.0V is applied across a resistor of 20Ω, what is the amount of current flowing?"
流れる電流は何アンペアか
電車の車掌さんアンペア
that "'I want to be a train conductor' amps" will be the kind of answer turned in!
なんって答えだ
そんなに不安
Are you that nervous?
いや
N-No, it's not that bad.
そういうワケじゃなく
Relax. It'll be fine.
落ち着いて
大丈夫よ
えっと
You're...
A-Ah, Otonashi.
音無
音無君
Otonashi-kun.
I don't know your name, either.
オレもあんたの名前知らない
Me? I'm Tachibana.
ワタシ
たちばな
And your given name?
下は
Given name? Kanade.
下
奏
Tachibana Kanade.
タチバナ　カナデ
It has a beautiful ring to it.
美しい響き
TL Note: Kanade's name means to play a melody or song.
As the name's meaning implies, a very nice, lyrical name.
名のとおり音を奏でるような
イイ名前だと思った
Thank you. You've helped me calm down.
ありがとう
タチバナのおかげで落ち着いたよ
じゃ　がんばって
Okay, good luck.
タチバナ　カナデ
It's Tachibana Kanade.
うん　そんな名前だったわ
Oh yeah, I remember now.
知ってたんじゃないかよ
So you knew!
忘れてただけよ
No, I had forgotten.
ほら　はじめるぞ
Okay, we're starting. Take your seats.
座れ
なんだ　記憶ねえのに
Huh? Why can I solve these so easily when I don't have any memories?
なんでこんなにすらすら解けるんだ　オレ
Don't solve the problems too diligently.
問題をマジメに解いちゃダメよ
消えるファクターになりかねない
It could become a prompt for disappearance.
Shoot.
I'm not supposed to be taking this seriously.
まじめにうけちゃダメなんだった
Okay. Pass forward the tests from the back.
はい　じゃ後ろから集めて
What the hell is that?!
なんじゃ　ありゃ
グランドから超巨大な筍がにょきにょきと
A huge bamboo stalk is growing out of the field!
阿呆日向
You're a moron, Hinata.
Damn. So useless.
ったく　仕方ないわね
いつも一人で歩いてた
あなたがミスしたときのために
I placed a propulsion system under
your seat, just in case you messed up.
いすの下に推進エンジンをつんでおいたのよ
What did it feel like to be an astronaut?
どうだった
ちょっとした宇宙飛行士気分は
I crashed through the ceiling and instantly came back down!
一瞬で天井に激突して落下したよ
つか　推進エンジンなんてよく作れたな～
Besides, how did you even make a propulsion system?
I covered your screw up, so be thankful.
フォローしてあげたんだから
感謝なさいよ
作戦成功ね　竹山君
Looks like it went well, Takeyama-kun.
It went perfectly.
ぬかりありません
Also, call me Chr-
あと「クライスト」ッ
じゃ　次は高松君
You're up next, Takamatsu-kun.
What will I do?
ワタシが何か
It's your turn to attract attention.
みんなの気を引く役ね
I-I thought that was Hinata-san's role.
そ　それは日向さんの役割では
Ever heard of the boy who cried wolf?
「狼少年」の話　知ってる
Repeated lies lose their effectiveness.
繰り返されるウソは信憑性を失っていく
そういうワケ
Exactly.
ま　まさか
I-Is that why you brought along this many people?
そのために　頭数を
I wonder.
さあ～
辞退を
I resign!
やるのよ
You're doing it.
Give up and fly gracefully. And right through the ceiling.
あきらめて飛べ
そして天井に激突しろ
I must think of something that will gather everyone's attention.
絶対全員が注目する何かを考え出さなくては
あの～
What should I do for the next set of answers?
つぎの回答はどのようにすればイインでしょう
Man, but you have it easy.
お前はイイよな
小細工するだけだから
You only have to swap papers. You don't have to fly on top of it.
とばないし
なに言ってんですか
What are you talking about?
こっちだって大きなリスクを
I'm responsible for a more critical part of the mission.
はらんだ任務を帯びてるんですよ
では　かわってください
Then please change with me.
イヤですよ
I don't want to!
See, so you do prefer your seat!
やっぱそっちのほうがイインじゃないか
Must be nice to have such a good luck of the draw!
くじ運がよくてよかったな～
これはボクにしかできない心計の要る作業なんだ
This is delicate work that only I can accomplish!
そっちは飛べだけで
All you have to do is fly. It's not like you have to use your head.
頭つかわなくてイイじゃないですか
なんだと　こっちはバカってか
What? Are you calling us idiots?!
Hey! Stop fighting!
こら　ケンカするな
Crap!
やばっ
Sorry! We were arguing over one of the answers.
すまん
答え合わせでもめていた
今は決着がついた
We just came to a conclusion.
日向が０点だったことがわかった
We concluded that Hinata got a zero.
Everything's all right. No problem!
万事オーケーだ　もう問題ない
Sorry for being so noisy. Everything's good!
騒がしくて　わるかった
もう大丈夫だ
I see.
そう
バカ
You idiot!
だれがだ
Who is?
So, how should I answer the next test?
で　次の回答はどうすればいいんでしょう
What's the next subject?
教科はなんだっけ
It's World History.
世界史です
Then fill in the blanks assuming the Earth has been taken over by aliens.
じゃあ　地球は宇宙人に侵略されていることにして
全問答えておいて
はい　じゃ後ろから集めて
All right. Pass forward the answer sheets.
I suppose I have no choice.
やるしかないか
What's the matter?
どうしたの　そこのキミ
Sensei, I must confess.
先生
実はワタシ…
着痩せするタイプなんです
I'm actually well built!
What do you think?
どうですか
Sure, now take your seat.
わかったから　座りなさい
Yes, ma'am.
はい
それでも私は
ったく　よくもまあ　あんな浅はかな案を
Damn, I can't believe you were able to pull off something that stupid so proudly.
自信をもって遂行できたものね
I was confident it would work.
自信あったんですが
Since you wouldn't expect it from me.
意外性があるといいますか
Because it goes against my character,
見かけによらないといいますか
that I would secretly train.
かげで鍛えてるので
いいから　上着ろよ
Put your shirt on already.
It went well this time too, right, Takeyama-kun?
今回も首尾はバッチシね
竹山君
抜かりはありません
Of course. Now, would you start calling me Chr-
そろそろ　クラッ
Okay! Next up is Ooyama-kun.
次は大山君
やっぱり来たか
I knew it'd come to me!
ボク持ちネタなんかないよ
I don't have anything I can pull off.
大山君の席は天使の斜め後ろで近いじゃない
Your seat is close to Tenshi, diagonally behind her.
A-Ah, right! Then maybe I won't have to pull off a stunt, right?
え　そ　そうだね
じゃもしかしてネタやらなくてイイ
Sure, all you have to do is confess your love to Tenshi.
うん　天使に告白してくれたら
うん　うん？　なんだって
Right! Wait, what was that again?
天使に告白するのよ
I said confess your love to Tenshi.
「こんなときに場所も選ばずごめんなさい
"I'm sorry to say it at a time like this, without even considering the place.
あなたのことがずっと好きでした
I've always been in love with you. Please go on a date with me."
付き合ってください」って
Do exactly that, and you won't have to be launched.
言われたとおりにすれば飛ばないですむわよ
ちッ　告るだけでいいのかよ
Damn! All he has to do is ask her out?
なんかずるいぜ
That's not fair.
Come on! Put yourself in my shoes!
そんな
ボクの身にもなってよ
You've only suffered physical injury,
but I'll have tremendous emotional scars!
そっちは肉体的ダメージですんだかもしれないけど
ボクはメンタルのダメージがすごいよ
だって女の子に告白するなんて初めてだよ
This will be my first time asking a girl out!
しかも　振られるのがわかってるんだよ
And I even know ahead of time she's going to turn me down!
うぶなやつめ
What a baby. This will be perfect practice for him.
練習にはちょうどイイじゃないですか
Unlike you, I don't need practice!
ボクは日向君と違って　練習なんかしない
本気の恋しかしないんだよ
I only need true love!
What? Are you saying I cheat on people?!
なんだっと
オレが偽りに染まった薄汚い恋でもしてるってんのかよ
Hey! You guys stop fighting!
こら
てめえらケンカするな
Sorry! Yuri's a little emotionally unstable.
すまん　ゆりの調子が不安定だ
原因は昨夜夢に日向が出てきて
Because last night, Hinata showed up in her dream and-
Don't think that the me from today and tomorrow will be the same.
今日のオレと明日のオレが同じオレだと思うな
Watch out.
気をつけな～
That's what he said, and Yuri just proved it.
と忠告してきたことによる
そして今その忠告が事実であることを
ゆりが証明しちまったところなんだ
Are there two Hinata-kun's?
日向君は二人いるの
Y-Yeah... that's right.
ああ　そういうことになる
三人以上いるかもしれない？
Is there a chance that there's more than three of him?
え？　あ　ありえる
Huh? Oh, uh... it's possible.
I'm sorry to hear that.
お気の毒に
今はもう落ち着いてるから
Everything's calmed down, so don't worry. It's good now.
心配するな　問題ない
All okay.
万事オーケーだ
気遣いありがとうな
Sorry to worry you.
How many of me are there, did you say?
だれが三人以上いるだ
Who's emotionally unstable?
だれが情緒不安定よ
こらこら　フォローしてやったのに
Hey now, I covered for you guys, so don't give me that.
なんだ　その言い草は
お前らの自業自得だ
You all brought it upon yourselves.
So, what should the next set of answers be?
で　次の解答はどのようにすればいいんでしょう
What's the subject?
教科は
It's English.
TL Note: Katakana is a Japanese character set generally used to represent foreign languages. In English class, they would be expected to write in the Roman alphabet.
英語です
じゃあ　すべて片仮名で答えておいて
Then answer all the questions in katakana.
Okay. Pass forward the answer sheets.
はい　じゃあ　後ろから集めて
Tachibana-san!
タチバナさん
こんな時に場所も選ばずごめんなさい
I'm sorry for saying this now, without even considering the place!
I've always loved you! Please go on a date with me!
あなたのことがずっと好きでした
付き合ってください
Then please consider the place.
じゃあ　時と場所を選んで
そこ　座れ
You. Take your seat.
はい
Yes, sir.
Ah, he's done it. Now he's-
ああぁぁ　やっちまった
とぶッ
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
Hey, hey! Wait a damn minute!
こーら　こら　待って
なによ　寄ってこないでよ
What? Don't come near me!
なんでおれが飛ばされるんだよ
Why was it that I took flight?!
Well, Ooyama-kun suffered a deep enough wound to his heart.
だって　大山君は十分心に傷を負ったんじゃない
それで　なんでおれなんだよ
Well why did you choose me?! I don't get this at all!
わけわかんねえよ
That aside, everyone, let's have lunch.
それよりも　みんな
お昼にしましょう
モエのつきカミガミ
Rooftop
Classroom Building A
Are you prepared, Takeyama-kun?
抜かりはないわね　竹山君
Absolutely, and it's Christ.
完璧です
そして　「クライスト」です
あ　こっちは飛ばされて天井に激突して
I've been taking flight and crashing into the ceiling, here.
あと何回こんな目に遭うんだ
How many more times do I have to go through this?
テスト期間中ずっとよ
Throughout the exam period.
明日はメンバー変えよぜ
Let's change the team members tomorrow!
Matsushita-kun and T.K. look heavy.
松下君とかティーケーって　重そうだもの
軽いからって選ぶなよ
Don't choose us by weight!
つーか
Besides, taking flight with the chair sure has an impact, but everyone will get bored quick.
いくら椅子ごと飛ぶのがインパクトあるっつっても
皆飽きてくるぜ
「あはん　また飛んでるわ」みたいに
"Oh look, there he goes again."
もう見ねえぜ
They'll even stop turning around soon enough!
だから錐揉みさせたり
That's why I'm adding some spice.
ギミックを加えていくのよ
What's waiting for us from here on? You're scaring your allies!
なにが俺達を待ってんだよ
怖えよ　仲間だろ
だから　協力なさいよ
Then participate!
I said you're scaring us!
だから　怖えよ
明日も告白させられるのかな
Is she going to make me confess love again tomorrow?
今度は　下も脱ぐか
Maybe I should take my pants off, too, next time.
The operation is nearly perfect.
作戦はほぼ完璧だ
けど　こんなことで　なにかが変わるんだろか
But, will something really change by doing this?
結局
We're just making a commotion, as usual, and the calm returns, as usual.
いつものように俺達が一方的にドタバタと騒ぎ立てて
それで　いつものように落ち着きを取り戻してゆく
それだけだと思っていた
I thought that's all there would be to this.
そして　テスト期間が終わり
And so, the exam period ended.
Hallway
before the
Faculty Lounge
Teacher's Building 1st Floor
タチバナ　どうした
Tachibana?
What's wrong? Did something happen?
なにかあったんのか
なにも
Nothing.
The Following Day
流れはじめたわ
It's starting to mill around.
おっ　なにが
What is?
The rumour about Tenshi getting a zero on all subjects.
天使の全教科零点の噂
Seriously?
まじかよ
しかも
And that the answers were all intended to make the teachers look like fools.
教師を馬鹿にしたような回答ばかりだったと
They're even saying that?
そんなことまで…
What did you guys do?
なにをやってきたんだ　貴様らは
飛んだり　錐揉みしたり
We flew, added some spice,
and eventually we even flew out the window.
しまいには窓から飛び去ったさ
なんだそれは
What the heck?
でも　教師は そんなの天使自身じゃなく
But don't the teachers know that it's not Tenshi herself, but someone's prank?
だれかのしわざだってわかるだろう
How many times do I need to tell you? The teachers can't figure that out.
何度言わせるの
そんなことは教師にはわからない
現実と同じ
Just like the in real world, if the Student Council President were to turn in an exam with ridiculous answers,
生徒会長がふまじめな答案を提出してきた
then of course they're going to summon Tenshi to yell at her, just the same.
なら　天使自身を呼び出して
叱るに決まってるでしょう
So that's what happened, back then.
あの時がそうだったのか
タチバナは弁解したんだろか
Do you think Tachibana tried to explain?
I don't know. Besides, it's in every subject.
さあね
しかも　全教科だしね
全教科の教師にどうやって弁解するのよって話よ
How would she explain it to all the teachers?
From the teachers' eyes, well, it must seem like a one person rebellion.
教師からして見れば
まあ　一人きりの反乱ってとこだろうな
A one person rebellion...
一人きりの反乱
Gym
そして　数日後
And so, several days later...
それは　全校集会で告げられた
It happened during the school assembly.
Therefore, Tachibana Kanade-san will be resigning from her seat on the Student Council as of today.
というわけでありまして
立花奏さんは本日をもって生徒会長を辞任
そんな
Instead, Naoi-kun,
つきましては副会長の直井君が生徒会長代理として…
What?
the Vice President, will be taking over the seat as a deputy.
She's not resigning. She's being removed.
辞任じゃなく　解任ね
Yurippe.
百合っぺ
果たして
Now that she's one of the ordinary students
without any authority, will she be able to stop us?
一般生徒になり下がり 大義名分を失った彼女に
私達が止められるかしら
今夜
Tonight, we'll do Operation Tornado again.
オペレーション「トルネード」　決行よ
その曲　巌沢が残していた最後の曲なんだ
It's the final piece Iwasawa left behind.
へーそんな曲に
Was it all right for me to put lyrics to a piece like that?!
わたしが歌詞つけてよかったんですか
そうだな
Well, I guess it all depends on how people will react to the song, and to the second generation of GirlDeMo.
この新曲「サウザンド　エネミーズ」と
Spending time with you, who's always so displeased,
fukigensou na kimi to sugoshite
不機嫌そうな君と過ごして
第二期「ガールデモン」に皆が反応してくれるかどうか
それ次第だな
分かったことが一つあるよ
I've come to understand one thing,
wakatta koto ga hitotsu aru yo
わかったことがひとつあるよ
そんな無理して　戦うことに必死
You're only pretending to be that way, while in a frantic struggle.
sonna furi shite tatakau koto ni hisshi
そんなふりして戦うことに必死
なあ
Hey.
うん
俺達はなにと戦うんだ
What do... we fight against...?
Against whatever gets in our way, obviously.
それりゃ邪魔するやつだよ
I never want you to change; like a block of ice,
itsumademo kaenaide kouri no you ni
いつまでも　変えないで　氷のように
だれが邪魔しに来るんだよ
Who's going to get in our way?
来るとしたら天使だろう
Who other than Tenshi?
いや　あの生徒会長代理が来るかもしれないぜ
Or, maybe that deputy president.
夏の日差し　暑くても　溶けずにいてね
Never melt, even for the hottest rays of the sun.
natsu no hizashi atsukutemo tokezu ni ite ne
夏の陽射し暑くても溶けずにいてね
He's an NPC, isn't he?
そいつは一般生徒だろ
撃っちゃダメだろ
We can't shoot him.
きっと先に美しい　氷河があるよ
Surely, at the end of this path, a beautiful glacier awaits,
kitto saki ni utsukushii hyouga ga aru yo
きっと先に　美しい氷河があるよ
Ah, right.
おっ　そっか
来るのか　天使は
Will Tenshi come?
形あるそんな心
Such a heart, if you look closely, is surely within everyone.
katachi aru sonna kokoro dare datte kidzukeba motteru
形あるそんな心　誰だって気づけば持ってる
誰だって　気付けば持ってる
You have one as well.
kimi mo motteru
君も持ってる
I'm so hungry I can barely even walk,
onaka ga suite arukenakunatte
お腹が空いて歩けなくなって
おっ 来た
She's here!
And I've come to understand one thing.
wakatta koto ga hitotsu aru yo
わかったことがひとつあるよ
分かったことが　一つあるよ
Let's take her down before she deploys her Guard Skills.
「ガードスキル」発動前に
いくぜ
待って　撃つな
Wait, don't shoot!
どうして
Why not?
やるべきこと　先送りにして
I've been putting off all the things I should do,
yaru beki koto sakiokuri ni shite
やるべきこと先送りにして
様子がおかしい
Something's not right.
どうおかしいんだよ
やりたいことばっかやってる
And only ever doing what I want,
yaritai koto bakka yatteru
やりたいことばっかやってる
What's not right?
わかんねえけど
I don't know.
戦意がないというか
But, she looks like she's not here to fight. I don't sense any hostility from her.
ごはん食べて　戦うに託しよう
無抵抗な気が…
Eat your dinner and let's prepare for battle.
gohan tabete tatakau shitaku shi yo
ご飯食べて戦う支度しよ
She looks more like she's here for something else.
違う目的でフラッとやってきたような
なんだよ　それ
What do you mean?
I want to always possess a will of iron,
itsumademo motteitaiyo hagane no you na
いつまでも　持っていたいよ　鋼のような
いつまでも持ってたよ鋼のような
どんなものも通さない頑固な意地を
That is sturdy and won't let anything pass.
donna mono mo toosanai ganko na iji wo
どんなものも通さない頑固な意地を
きっと今も立ちつくして守りの途中
We're at a standstill, trying to protect something,
kitto ima mo tachitsukushite mamori no tochuu
きっと今も立ちつくして守りの途中
天使？外はなにしてるの
Tenshi?! What's going on outside?
And in our paths, there are innumerable enemies;
yukute ni ha kazoekirenai
行く手には　数え切れない
行く手には　数えきれない
敵がいて　あたしを待ってる
They're waiting for me...
teki ga ite atashi wo matteru
敵がいてあたしを待ってる
どうしますか
What should we do?
Hold on a minute.
ちょっと　待って
What is this? Something's not right with her.
なんなんの　様子がおかしい
君にも待ってる
They're waiting for you as well.
kimi ni mo matteru
君にも待ってる
あいつ　なにを
What is she doing?
あれは全校生徒がいっさい手を出さない
That's the infamous mapo doufu that no one in the school orders because it's so spicy!
激辛で有名なマーボ豆腐
どういうこと　なぜあんなものを
Why? Why is she buying that?
アタシたちに食わせて　一矢報いようってんの
Is she going to make us eat it and get her revenge?
Come on, let's forge onward, crossing any number of bridges.
saasa susumou ikutsu mono kakehashi
さあさ進もういくつもの架け橋
だんだん進もう　いくつもの駆け出し
ゆりっぺさん
Yurippe-san, the excitement has reached its peak.
盛り上がりは最高潮を迎えていると見受けられますが
We'll always be together, just like lovers,
itsumademo isho dakara koibito no you ni
いつまでも　一緒だから　恋人のように
いつまでも一緒だから恋人のように
指示を
Your orders, please.
行った先に壮大な景色が待つよ
Surely, at the end of this path, a grand scenery awaits us,
kitto saki ni soudai na keshiki ga matsu yo
きっと先に　壮大な景色が待つよ
Sure...
When that time comes, I'll listen to all your pent-up feelings,
sono toki ha tamatteita sono kimochi zenbu kiiteyaru
その時は溜まっていたその気持ちぜんぶ聞いてやる
その時は黙っていた
Turn them on!
回せ
まわしてください
Spin it, please.
その気持ち全部聞いてやる
I'll tell you mine too.
kimi ni mo kikasu
君にも聞かす
Every single one of them.
tappuri kikasu
たっぷり聞かす
Food Court
School Cafeteria
Mapo Doufu
Hey! That's the infamous mapo doufu that no one orders because it's so spicy!
なんだお前
それ誰も頼まないことで有名な激辛マーボドウフじゃん
猛者でも白いご飯と一緒に頼んで
The best way I've seen to eat it is to pour it over rice to buffer the pain.
どんぶりにして食うんだぜ
これつかんちまったんだから　仕方ないだろ
Well, I grabbed this, so I don't have a choice.
一口で激辛
One bite and I'm on fire!
Hey, but it's good.
でもうまいぞ
日向　食ってみるよ
Give it a try, Hinata.
What?! You're joking.
うあ　嘘だろ
じゃあ　一口だけ
Okay, then just one bite.
It hurts! It's hot! It's spicy!
痛い　辛い　つーか痛い
しかし　あとから来るこの風味
But, this flavour that follows the pain...
なるほど　こいつは味わえる甲斐かもしれない
I see. This stuff really is good.
だろう　こんなうまいマーボドウフ
See? You've never had mapo doufu that tasted so good, right?
食ったことねえだろう
案外あたりメニューなのかもな
Maybe it's some sort of secret winner.
それ天使が買った食券よ
That's the ticket Tenshi bought.
こ　これ
T-This?
Yeah.
そッ
これ食いたかっただけなんだな
So, she just wanted to eat this.
きっと　これはあいつの大好物なんだよ
This must be her favourite flavour.
そんなささやかな幸せまで奪っちまった　オレ
I even took away such a small piece of happiness from her...
天使は人だ
Tenshi must be a human.
失意の底で慰めに好物のマーボドウフを食べにくる天使が
What kind of angel comes to eat her
favourite mapo doufu to comfort herself?
どこにいる
As the Student Council President, she couldn't let us run loose and promote disobedience.
生徒会長としての義務から
風紀を乱しまくる私たちを野放しにしておけなかったんだ
私たちがギルドで兵器を生み出したから
Because we started to build weapons at the Guild,
she began developing Guard Skills to fight against us.
彼女も対抗して「ガードスキル」を生み出し始めた
Is that how all this started? How ridiculous...
これがことの顛末か
滑稽ね
まだ神への糸口もつかめていなかったなんて
I haven't even found a hint to God, yet.
You know...
もしかしたらさ
...maybe Tenshi, as she is now, could join our side.
今の天使なら
おれたちの仲間になれるんじゃないかな
はあぁぁッ！？
Don't be stupid!
馬鹿言ってんじゃねえぜ
Do you know how many of us died because of her?!
これまでどれだけの仲間がやつの餌食に
Well, none really died, but...
いや　餌食つーか　皆ぴんぴんしてけど
どれだけ痛めつけられてきたか
Do you know how much pain we've gone through?
そうだそうだ
Yeah! She was docile today, but who knows when she'll become aggressive again!
今日はおとなしかったかもしれねえが
いつまた牙を向くか
寝首掻かれかねねぇぜ
She could get us right when we drop our guard!
愚問だったな　音無君
That was a silly question, wasn't it, Otonashi-kun?
みたいだな
Seems so.
俺はどうして
Why did I make such a foolish proposal?
そんな馬鹿げた提案をしてしまったんだろ
It's because I imagined how she would be eating...
...mapo doufu alone, at a table in the corner of the room.
Having lost all trust, and her position, she looked painfully lonely.
I've always walked this path alone; when I look back, everyone is so far away.
itsumo hitori de aruiteta furikaeru to minna ha tooku
いつもひとりで歩いてた　振り返るとみんなは遠く
それは　食券を一人で買い求めて
いつも一人で歩いてた
Even so, I kept on walking. That was my strength.
soredemo atashi ha aruita sore ga tsuyosa datta
それでもあたしは歩いた　それが強さだった
この学食の隅の席で
●
一人でマーボドウフを食べている彼女の姿を
振り返るとみんなは遠く
●
思い描いてしまったからだ
信用をも失い役目も失った彼女のその姿は
もう何も怖くない
"Nothing frightens me any longer", I mumble softly.
mou nanimo kowakunai sou tsubuyaitemiseru
もう何も恐くない　そう呟いてみせる
痛々しいほどに孤独だった
．
●
そうつぶやいてみせる
いつか　人は一人になって
Eventually, everyone ends up alone,
itsuka hito ha hitori ni natte
いつか人は一人になって
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
And is left with only their memories.
omoide no naka ni ikiteku dake
思い出の中に生きてくだけ
．
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
In order to appreciate even sorrow and continue smiling,
kodoku sae aishi waratterareru you ni
孤独さえ愛し笑ってられるように
．
私は戦うんだ
I'll keep on fighting,
atashi ha tatakaunda
あたしは戦うんだ
涙なんて見せないんだ
I won't show you my tears.
namida nante misenainda
涙なんて見せないんだ
What are you guys?!
なんだ貴様らは
一般生徒よ
They're NPCs.
そこまでだ
That's enough.
いろいろと容疑はあるが
I have various charges against you all,
とりあえず　時間外活動の校則違反により
but for the time being, I'll have you sent to the Introspection Room...
全員　反省室へ連行する
...for violating school rules regarding activity hours.
ぼくが生徒会長となったからには
Now that I'm the Student Council President, you will not be left with an easy way out.
貴様らには甘い選択はない
Take them away.
連れていけ
Next Episode Preview
Take them away.
What's wrong with that guy...
That's the deputy Student Council President...
Naoi Ayato-sama.
Dora dora. Dealer Mangan!
Don't be freaking ridiculous!
We need Tenshi.
You dare to rebel? Against God?
Hand Sonic: Version 2.
Reflect on what?!
Are you going to accept that?
It's them...
Please, God!
Your life should have been the real deal, too!